# Jeremy Springman

PDRI-DevLab University of Pennsylvania Updated Wednesday 18<sup>th</sup> September, 2024 ☑: jspr@sas.upenn.edu ☐: jrspringman.github.io ♠: https://github.com/jrspringman ੴ: https://shorturl.at/ixTW8

I am an applied researcher helping donors and civil society strengthen democratic institutions and practices in aid-receiving countries. Currently, I serve as co-PI on the Machine Learning for Peace (ML4P) project, teach a course on data science for global development, and lead several other USAID-funded research projects. To investigate these topics, my research uses machine learning techniques including natural language processing and forecasting and causal inference tools including field and survey experiments. I am particularly interested in developing novel design and measurement strategies to generate rigorous evidence from projects with limited budgets and challenging implementation environments.

# Academic Appointments

### University of Pennsylvania, PDRI-DevLab

Senior Research Associate & Director of Civic Research

July 2022 - Present

### Duke University, DevLab@Duke

Senior Research Associate	July 2021 – June 2022
Post-Doctoral Research Associate	July 2019 - June 2021
Pre-Doctoral Research Associate	January 2019 – July 2019

### Education

### University of Pennsylvania

Ph.D. in Comparative Politics & International Relations	2019
M.A. in Political Science	2015

### University of Pittsburgh

B.A. in Politics & Philosophy (Honors College) 2012

## Refereed Academic Publications

The Political Economy of NGO Service Provision: Evidence from an Ancillary Field Experiment World Politics, 2022 (DOI: S0043887122000107)

The Effect of Government Repression on Civil Society: Evidence from Cambodia International Studies Quarterly, 2022 (DOI: sqac028)
First author (with Edmund Malesky, Lucy Right, and Erik Wibbels)

Oil Discoveries and Political Windfalls: Evidence on Presidential Support in Uganda Political Science Research & Methods, 2023 (DOI: psrm.2023.14)
Second author (with Laura Paler, Guy Grossman, and Jan Pierskalla)

### **Under Review**

Aid Flows and Incumbency Advantage: Evidence from NGO Projects in Uganda Revise & Resubmit at World Politics

Fostering civic Engagement in Polarized, Autocratic Regimes: Evidence from a Field Experiment in Ethiopia

with Sewareg Adamu, David Dow, Fitsum Hailu, Mesele Mengsteab, and Juan Tellez

The Effect of Government Intervention on the Operational Decisions of NGOs: Evidence from a Survey Experiment in Three Electoral Autocracies

with Erik Wibbels, Maria Nagawa, Graeme Robertson, and Simon Hollerbauer

The Effect of Closing Civic Space on Aid: Evidence from 2.3 Million Donor Projects with Lucille Right and Erik Wibbels

## Selected Policy Reports

Zimbabwe Governance Indicators Analysis Prepared for USAID Zimbabwe March 2024

Resurgent Authoritarian Influence: Evidence from Machine-Generated, Cross-National Data Prepared for USAID Analytic Task on Authoritarian Resurgence and Influence August 2023

Radio and Social Media in Ghana Assessment Report

Prepared for USAID Ghana

July 2023 (DEC ID: coming soon)

The Effect of Social Ties on Engagement & Cohesion: Evidence from Ethiopian University Students Prepared for USAID Innovation, Technology, & Research Hub

April 2023 (DEC ID: PA-021155)

Resiliency Cambodia Impact Evaluation Findings Report

Prepared for USAID Cambodia

August 2022 (DEC ID: PA-00Z-KBD)

Retrospective of USAID's Response to Pandemic-Enabled Democratic Backsliding

Prepared for USAID Democracy, Human Rights, and Governance Center

January 2022 (DEC ID: PA-00Z-6HN)

### **Policy Writing**

Charting a Course for Applied Research in Peacebuilding

First author (with Heather Huntington and Erik Wibbels)

Forthcoming in "A Positive Peace: Towards an Evidence-Based Peacebuilding" (United States Institute of Peace)

Report of the Advisory Panel for the Governance of Human Rights Organizations With Mohamed Arafa and David Siegel (for Amnesty International)

### External Awards & Grants

### United States Department of Defense Minerva Research Initiative

Modeling Climate-Induced Societal Adaptation and Population Displacement with New Machine-Coded Environmental Event Data: \$1,500,000\* with Erik Wibbels and Iriana Marinov

### **Open Society Foundations**

Special Projects & Crisis Response: \$250,000\* with Erik Wibbels

# USAID Democracy, Human Rights, and Governance Bureau

- Tracking Authoritarian Resurgence and Democratic Institutions and Spaces: \$600,000\*
- Distinguishing Legitimate, Superficial, and Fabricated Anti-corruption Campaigns: \$46,690
- Central American Regional Media Project Impact Evaluation: \$75,554 (Phase 1-2)
- Zimbabwe Governance Indicators Analysis: \$37,894
- Swift Expertise and Grounded Analytics: \$500,000\*
- Analytic Task on Authoritarian Resurgence and Influence: \$99,737\*
- INSPIRES Flexible Response Funds: \$83,000\*

# United States Agency for International Development (USAID) Bureau for Policy, Planning, and Learning

Local Evaluation and Evidence Support (LEES): \$98,060

### University of Antwerp

Foreign Information Manipulation and Interference: \$12,500\* with Erik Wibbels

### USAID Ghana Monitoring Evaluation and Learning (MEL) Platform

Radio Station Managers Survey: \$30,000\*

### USAID Innovation, Technology, and Research Hub

LASER PULSE (with Mesele Mengsteab, Juan Tellez, and David Dow): \$250,000

### USAID Mission to Cambodia

Local Organizations—Movement Towards Self-Reliance: \$225,000\*

#### **National Science Foundation**

2018 - 2019 Doctoral Dissertation Research Improvement Grant (SES-1747642): \$14,996

### Anonymous private philanthropic foundation

2018 Research Grant: \$38,600

### American Political Science Association Centennial Grant

2017 - 2018 Grant Recipient: \$1,100

### Teaching & Advising

### University of Pennsylvania: Instructor

Global Development: Intermediate Topics in Politics, Policy, and Data

Spring 2024

Course website: jrspringman.github.io/psci3200-globaldev/

Fels Institute of Government Lab Capstone Partner

Spring 2024

# Local Evaluation and Evidence Support (LEES): Academic Lead

The LEES activity supports efforts by the Bureau for Policy, Planning, and Learning (PPL) to promote localization of USAID activities by increasing the capacity of local partners and strengthening networks that connect these organizations.

# Recent Invited Talks & Events

Perry World House Forum (Washington, D.C.)	Oct, 2024
Vienna University of Economics and Business (Vienna, Austria)	Sept, 2024
International Civil Society Centre (Remote)	June, 2024
Schloss Dagstuhl AI for Social Good Seminar (Wadern, Germany)	Feb, 2024
Foris International Ethical AI Manifesto Launch Event (Remote)	Nov, 2023
World Bank EngageFest Webinar (Remote)	Nov, 2023
United States Department of State (Remote)	Jul, 2023
Community of Democracies Enabling and Protecting Civil Society (Remote)	Jun, 2023
United Nations Data Strategy Community Series (Remote)	Jun, 2023
US Agency for International Development Tech Tuesdays Series (Remote)	Jun, 2023
United States Army 95th Civil Affairs Brigade (Fort Liberty, NC)	Jun, 2023
Social Impact Evidence for Impact Webinar Series (Remote)	May, 2023
Duke University US Army Governance Training (Durham, NC)	Feb, 2023
US Agency for International Development DRG Center (Washington, D.C.)	Feb, 2023
Vassar College Data Science & Society Colloquium (Poughkeepsie, NY)	Dec, 2022
Paris Peace Forum (Paris, France)	Nov, 2022
International Civic Forum (London, UK)	Nov, 2022
Big Data for Development & Governance Conference (Philadelphia, PA)	Oct, 2022
International Center for Not-for-Profit Law (Remote)	Jun, 2022

# Invited Public Engagement

Amnesty International Advisory Panel for the Governance of Human Rights Organizations	2024
Foris International Ethical AI Manifesto Contributor	2024
3ie Civil Society Evidence Gap Maps Advisory Group Member	2023